Olawole Ogunfunminiyi frankfurtmacmoses@gmail.com +1(832) 8150073

PROFILE / SUMMARY

Frankfurt is a certified Project Manager, Business/Data Analyst with experience in software development methodologies and advance data driving methods, with proven records of delivering business applications and data products having come from these two backgrounds. **EXPERTISE**

Project Management and Business Analysis

- MS Project, Visio, Expert Level MS Office user
- SDLC Project Management
- Agile Scrum
- Universal Modelling Languages
- Use Case Diagrams
- Flow Chat Processes
- Impact Analysis
- Functional Requirements Gathering
- Communication Skills
- Problem Solving Skills
- Flexibility/Adaptability

Software/Engineering

- Reproducible Research and Report Generation with R
- Data visualization with R ggplot2
- Knowledge of Business component with JEE, Linux Scripts
- Knowledge of Object-Oriented S/W Design and Development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business/Data Analyst

Osun State Government/Word Bank, Nigeria

April 2014 – December 2019

- Delivered the approved project chatter and project management plan for building 195 megawatts electricity to power the state secretariat to be financed by Exim bank, U.S.A between 2014-2017.
- Project Managed the team responsible for design of Big Data Analytics usage for strategic repositioning of Bureau of Social Services (BOSS) for effective Monitoring and Evaluation of government's projects to support effective budgeting by Ministry of Finance and Economic Planning.
- Review proposals, technical/user requirement documents from service providers of application automation to government and scheduling products that ensure core business processes run faster, more accurately and without interruption.
- Drafted operation processes for submitting reports and made presentations in conjunction with Ministry of Information, Science and Technology to review usage of bulk Microsoft licenses procured by the State Government of Osun.
- Identified key stakeholder and directly involved in gathering requirements for developing intricate algorithms based on deep-dive statistical
 analysis and predictive data modeling that were used to deepen relationships, strengthen longevity and personalize interactions with
 customers.
- Analyzed and processed complex data sets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Identified, measured and recommended improvement strategies for KPIs across all business areas.
- Responsible for parsing and merging datasets
- Directly involved information technology training for the Youth Employment and Social Support Operations (YESSO) activities of the World Bank / Osun State Government
- Trained R and Python Programmers regarding applicable regulatory guidelines and programming activities for the other supporting team in Monitoring and Evaluation department of YESSO project.

Business Analyst

ChamsSwitch Limited (a subsidiary of Chams Plc)

February 2012 - January 2014

Conducted JAD Sessions and interview with Stakeholders and SMES for requirement gathering, and planned meetings, daily scrum
meeting, sprint demo and retrospective meeting with 7-man team to develop web applications to extend the functionality of Base24 eps
Switch.

- Created clear, concise detailed user requirements specification (SRS) documents and user documents in accordance to guidelines and standards to enable developers interpret, design and develop the application with minimum guidance for implementation of installation of livery web payment gateway 5 weeks before the deadline.
- Created system requirement specification for step-by-step connection of many merchants to Ivery web payment gateway and bank ATMs
 to Base24 Switch before the establishment of Nigeria Central Switch.
- Produce process flow for creating monthly reports for the activities of junior staff including work allocation and training.
- Lead the UAT team of Paycollect (revenue collection application) software developers for testing and integration of Paycollect to core banking applications to guarantee that all user requirement specifications are accurately implemented. This ware done at the head offices of 15 Nigeria Banks within 8 months.

Junior Business Analyst

New Horizons Computer Learning Centre, Nigeria

November 2008 - November 2011

- Involved in Design and documentation of requirement gathering for of E-learning applications using Java/J2EE Technologies
- Gather and analyze requirements for various projects, collaborating with end users to access implementation implications and providing solutions
- Support Database Administrators in developing physical and logical database models
- Create and modify process flows for new release of existing software.
- Worked with other senior analyst to produce monthly report.

Data Analyst

MTN Nigeria

June 2006 - November 2008

- Worked with the project manager and business analyst for the development of E-ballot application
- Involved in logical modeling and physical modeling of application.
- Developed Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages and SQL Scripts using Oracle PL/SQL.
- Involved in creation of Conceptual Modeling covering all the business requirements.
- Loaded the data into database tables using SQL*loader from text and excel files.
- Developed data model, SQL Queries, SQL Query tuning process and Schemas.
- Created SQL*plus reports as per client's various needs, and developed business objects.
- Developed SQL scripts for Referential Integrity check, which checks validity of incoming data with master tables in database.
- Involved in updating procedures, functions, triggers, and packages for validation and loading of data into target table based on the current requirement.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

Graduate Diploma Computer Science – Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria

2017

Thesis Title: Comparative analysis of Pig and Hive

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business School Netherlands

2015

Thesis Title: Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics In Osun State, Nigeria BSC Soil Science – Obafemi Awolowo University – Nigeria 2003

CERTIFICATIONS

2008 Project Management Professional, PMP (ID: 1212004)

2007 Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java EE 1.4 Platform (SCWCD) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated

2006 Sun Certified Programmer for Java Platform (1.4) (SCJP) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated, Now Oracle Incorporation

2006 Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) Awarded by Oracle Incorporation

JOHN HOPKINS UNIVERSITY BLOOMBERG SCHOOL OF PUBLIC HEALTH VERIFIED CERTIFICATE - COURSERA

Data Science Toolbox Getting and Cleaning Data Reproducible Research R Programming Exploratory Data Analysis Statistical Inference